

# Mehmet Çağrı Eti

Knorrstrasse 29 – 80807 Munich, Germany

☐ +49 155 10485037 • ☑ cagri.eti@tum.de

## **Profile**

Master's student in Quantum Science and Technology at TUM with a B.S. in Physics (optics concentration) and additional Mechanical Engineering background. Experienced in R&D engineering, optical system design, simulation, and experimental analysis. International research experience in Germany and Türkiye, with a strong foundation in laboratory work, programming, and data analysis.

## **Education**

**Technical University of Munich (TUM)** Munich, Germany Oct 2024 - Present M.Sc. Quantum Science and Technology Middle East Technical University (METU) Ankara, Türkiye B.Sc. Physics, GPA: 3.54 / 4.00 (1.6 in German system) Sep 2018 - Jan 2024 **METU** Ankara, Türkiye B.Sc. Mechanical Engineering (additional coursework) Oct 2021 - Oct 2024 Universität Münster (WWU) Münster, Germany ERASMUS+ Exchange Apr 2022 - Sep 2022 İzmir Atatürk Lisesi Izmir, Türkiye High School Diploma, GPA: 88.75 / 100 2014 - 2018 Salihli BİLSEM Manisa, Türkiye

## Work Experience

#### Beko Global (previously Arçelik Global)

Istanbul, Türkiye

2008 - 2015

R&D Engineer

Aug 2023 - Nov 2024

- O Building optical systems/sensors for the detection of biological aerosols and particulate matter
- O Simulation and design of lighting systems, reflectors, etc.
- O Literature review and patent applications

TÜBİTAK UzayAnkara, TürkiyeResearch ScholarJun 2023 – Sep 2023

O Research on viscosity of various types of fuel (without combustion)

Senior-Schüler, Senior Student: Physics, Chemistry, Geography

- Collaboration with Axiom Space
- Worked on particle image velocimetry using MATLAB

MKE A.Ş.

Summer Practice

Ankara, Türkiye

Jun 2023 – Jul 2023

Observed various manufacturing techniques employed in the defense industry (specifically cartridges)

#### Department of Physics, University of Münster

Münster, Germany

Praktikum

Aug 2022 - Aug 2022

- O Programmed various subroutines with LabVIEW
- Analyzed waveforms and Fourier transformations
- O Prepared a comprehensive 30+ page protocol

## **Preply**

Physics Tutor Sep 2020 – Jan 2021

- O Assisted over 20 students with their national and/or entrance exams
- O Implemented specialized curriculums for students
- O Motivated many students and families

# **Further Skills**

**Technical Skills**: Over 3 years of lab experience in general physics, general chemistry, material physics and optics labs.

**Programming & Software**: MATLAB, Python, GCODE, LabVIEW, LaTeX, MS Excel, LTSpice, Siemens NX

Languages: English (Full Fluency), Turkish (Native), German (Beginner)

# **Honors & Awards**

2019–2023: High Honors Student, METU, Ankara, Türkiye 2012: First Lego League Challenge – Her Şeye Rağmen Award, Ankara, Türkiye

# References

<sup>&</sup>quot;Available upon request."